<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Nurturing Hope</title>
	<atom:link href="https://benjanim628.github.io/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://benjanim628.github.io</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 21:28:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Vrygrond Interviews</title>
		<link>https://benjanim628.github.io/vrygrond-interviews/</link>
					<comments>https://benjanim628.github.io/vrygrond-interviews/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 20:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benjanim628.github.io/?p=472</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I got the opportunity to go into Vrygrond and interview some people at Where Rainbows Meet. This was both an insightful and heartbreaking experience. I got one step closer to actually understanding what others have gone through. Below is an interview I held with Roger Daims, the senior cook at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I got the opportunity to go into Vrygrond and interview some people at Where Rainbows Meet. This was both an insightful and heartbreaking experience. I got one step closer to actually understanding what others have gone through.</p>
<p>Below is an interview I held with Roger Daims, the senior cook at Where Rainbows Meet. We discussed the role of Where Rainbows Meet and some key factors which contribute to the poverty in Vrygrond.</p>
<p><iframe width="750" height="422" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZmS8QW57aNA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This interview I held with Veronica, one of the women from the sewing department at Rainbows. We talked about her personal life and some of the issues in Vrygrond.</p>
<p><iframe width="750" height="422" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nOXAdfV4oPM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Here, I interviewed Shahram Jacobs, another women from Rainbow&#8217;s sewing department. She brought some valuable insight into the issues in Vrygrond and what is most needed as help.</p>
<p><iframe width="750" height="422" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GHUEbcMNuSQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://benjanim628.github.io/vrygrond-interviews/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where Rainbows Meet</title>
		<link>https://benjanim628.github.io/where-rainbows-meet/</link>
					<comments>https://benjanim628.github.io/where-rainbows-meet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 15:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benjanim628.github.io/?p=465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Where Rainbows Meet is a registered nonprofit organization which was founded in 2008. It is based in Vrygrond, Cape Town and provides the community with resources and opportunities to uplift their circumstances. They are devoted to community and business development.  Through programs, initiatives, and awareness events, they aim to improve [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.whererainbowsmeet.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Where Rainbows Meet</a> is a registered nonprofit organization which was founded in 2008. It is based in Vrygrond, Cape Town and provides the community with resources and opportunities to uplift their circumstances. <span>They are devoted to community and business development.  Through programs, initiatives, and awareness events, they aim to improve the chances of people from the community and therefore offer people from the community the opportunity to gain knowledge and experience within the organization.  </span></p>
<p><img src="https://benjanim628.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/IMG_20180822_154937-e1535642586671-300x98.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-454 alignleft" width="743" height="243" srcset="https://benjanim628.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/IMG_20180822_154937-e1535642586671-300x98.jpg 300w, https://benjanim628.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/IMG_20180822_154937-e1535642586671-768x252.jpg 768w, https://benjanim628.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/IMG_20180822_154937-e1535642586671-1024x335.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 743px) 100vw, 743px" /></p>
<div class="style-it019r4w" id="comp-it5kjnfe">
<div id="comp-it5kjnfeline" class="style-it019r4wline"></div>
</div>
<div data-packed="true" class="txtNew" id="comp-iqt74stk">
<h4 class="font_8"><strong>Where Rainbows Meet Complete Program List:</strong></h4>
<p class="font_8"><span>Selwyn Early Child Development centre (E.C.D.)</span></p>
<ul class="font_8">
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Day care programme</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Aftercare programme</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Parental courses</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Life Skills</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Spiritual dance</span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p class="font_8"><span>Youth Development</span></p>
<ul class="font_8">
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Generation For Change dance group</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Rainbow Chiefs soccer team</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Life skills</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>In schools programmes</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Out of school programmes</span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p class="font_8"><span>Women’s / income generating programmes</span></p>
<ul class="font_8">
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Siyazenzela sewing &amp; beadwork project</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Sibanye gardening project</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Nutritional program</span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p class="font_8"><span>Training and Development Program</span></p>
<ul class="font_8">
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Life skills</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>English courses</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Computer training</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Business courses</span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p class="font_8"><span>Health Centre</span></p>
<ul class="font_8">
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Free medical appointments</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Youth Hygiene Classes</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Support groups + ARVS follow ups</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Rape and drug counselling for women</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="font_8"><span>Feeding Scheme</span></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I am personally extremely impressed by the incredible work this organization does.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://benjanim628.github.io/where-rainbows-meet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Believe in a Child</title>
		<link>https://benjanim628.github.io/believe-in-a-child/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 19:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benjanim628.github.io/believe-in-a-child</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many underprivileged children are left at home in a stagnant environment. Today each of us has the chance to support a child and watch their growth and achievements. Where Rainbows Meet take in underprivileged children at a small fee and provide meals and loving support. Some families aren&#8217;t even able [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many underprivileged children are left at home in a stagnant environment. Today each of us has the chance to support a child and watch their growth and achievements.</p>
<p><img src="https://benjanim628.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/IMG_20180815_161727-300x225.jpg" alt="" class="size-medium wp-image-297 aligncenter" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://benjanim628.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/IMG_20180815_161727-300x225.jpg 300w, https://benjanim628.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/IMG_20180815_161727-768x576.jpg 768w, https://benjanim628.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/IMG_20180815_161727-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Where Rainbows Meet take in underprivileged children at a small fee and provide meals and loving support. Some families aren&#8217;t even able to pay this fee, but that is where we can all make a difference.</p>
<p>Sign up today and give a monthly donation of just R100 to support a child, giving them a brighter future. Log in at any time to see achievements of all your children.</p>
<p>Make A Difference Today.</p>
<pre class="code"><div style="" id="the_champ_fb_commenting"><div class="fb-comments" data-href="https://benjanim628.github.io/believe-in-a-child/" data-numposts="" data-width="100%" ></div></div><script type="text/javascript" src="//connect.facebook.net/en_US/sdk.js
    "></script><script>FB.init({xfbml:1,version: "v2.11"});</script></pre>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author</title>
		<link>https://benjanim628.github.io/author/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 17:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benjanim628.github.io/wp/?page_id=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am Benjamin Janowski, a grade 12 student at Constantia Waldorf School. At Waldorf the curriculum is unique in the way that every student is given the chance to go on a journey in the 12&#8217;th grade. This allows the student to learn new things and challenge themselves in new [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am Benjamin Janowski, a grade 12 student at Constantia Waldorf School.</p>
<p>At Waldorf the curriculum is unique in the way that every student is given the chance to go on a journey in the 12&#8217;th grade. This allows the student to learn new things and challenge themselves in new ways to allow for a broader learning experience.</p>
<p>I have chosen to devote my project to learning about, and helping the world, particularly those in underprivileged circumstances. I got to know a Non-Profit organization called <a href="http://www.whererainbowsmeet.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Where Rainbows Meet</a> where the most phenomenal things happen. Every week day more than 350 people are given nutritious meals while over 60 children from ages 3-8 are given a roof over their heads. These future leaders are given a safe space to play and a teacher to care for them, being separated from daily harsh conditions.</p>
<p>Not all children are able to afford this daily care but this is where the rest of us come into play.</p>
<p>We, the healthy leaders of today can make a difference in our community. Each step towards a better world counts, we will leave our marks behind today.</p>
<pre class="code"><div style="" id="the_champ_fb_commenting"><div class="fb-comments" data-href="https://benjanim628.github.io/author/" data-numposts="" data-width="100%" ></div></div><script type="text/javascript" src="//connect.facebook.net/en_US/sdk.js
    "></script><script>FB.init({xfbml:1,version: "v2.11"});</script></pre>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where It Started</title>
		<link>https://benjanim628.github.io/where-it-started/</link>
					<comments>https://benjanim628.github.io/where-it-started/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 14:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://benjanim628.github.io/wp/?p=5</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Beginning, November, 2017: I was sitting at the supper table with my mom. The subject of my upcoming class 12 project emerged and I began thinking of what I wanted to achieve through my project. I have always liked business &#8211; making money, and I love learning new things. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Beginning, November, 2017:</p>
<p>I was sitting at the supper table with my mom. The subject of my upcoming class 12 project emerged and I began thinking of what I wanted to achieve through my project. I have always liked business &#8211; making money, and I love learning new things. My mind went wild through random options which fitted these criteria when the idea hit me. I could raise money for a good cause – to help those in need and at the same time learn about my local community and history. On top of this I would learn great management skills, but best of all, I was going to give back to the surrounding local communities.</p>
<p>From this moment on I knew exactly what I planned to do. I was going to raise money through fundraisers, collect donations and then help a disadvantaged community through some project that I was going to think of. This turned out to be a lot more complicated than I had thought.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Figuring it out:</p>
<p>I began to brainstorm on how I was going to make my project a reality. The first step was to find a community in need, one that was not too big and one nearby. Living in South Africa made this possible but it would still not be an easy task. Isiyama Yethu came to mind, the township on the slopes of Hout Bay.</p>
<p>After setting my mind on a community I began to think how to get in touch. I thought of approaching churches or schools where I could possibly help out and get to know some people, after which I could ask specifically what their needs were. I had already thought of many things I could do but none of the ideas seemed feasible yet.</p>
<p>I sent emails to Isiyama Yethu Primary School but didn’t receive a reply. I then decided to drive there and talk to anyone I could so I decided to have a look at Google Maps street view to get familiar with the area. I was surprised to find that the area, although a township didn’t look to bad compared to other townships I had seen and heard of.</p>
<p>It was the new school year and I didn’t do much towards my project but one day I decided that it would be a smart idea perhaps to get in touch with other NGO’s to see what was already being done to help disadvantaged communities and what I could do to help. My mother told me about a women named Angela who was connected to the CCE and also started her own NGO named the Butterfly Art Project. This NGO was based in Vreygrond, a township near Retreat suffering from extreme poverty. I asked my mom if she could speak to Angela and arrange a meeting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://benjanim628.github.io/where-it-started/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
